A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Vice President, Office Files of William D. Carmichael FA711
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Vice President, Office Files of William D. Carmichael
1968-1989
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA711
14.4 Cubic Feet 12 standard record cartons
The Office Files of William D. Carmichael, Vice President of the Ford Foundation's Developing Country Programs (DCP) from 1981-1989, document his oversight of the program activities and administration of Foundation field offices around the world, and of New York-based program staff responsible for grants in developing countries. The collection spans 1968-1989 and consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports, grant proposals, conference materials and board of trustee meeting files. The files were transferred to and accessioned by the Ford Foundation Archives in 1990, and were fully processed in 2005.
Biographical note
William D. Carmichael was Vice President of the Ford Foundation, Developing Country Programs, from 1981-1989. Prior to that he served the Foundation as Head of the Middle East and Africa Office (1977-1981), Head of the Office for Latin America and the Caribbean (1971-1977) and Representative in the Brazil Office (1968-1971). Key accomplishments of Carmichael's tenure as Vice President include his role in advancing the development of a Women's Program, financing for worldwide activities in community resource management, the expansion of Foundation activities throughout southern Africa. Carmichael and his staff played a leading role within the U.S. philanthropic and scholarly communities in the formulation of policies towards the apartheid regime in South Africa. After leaving the Ford Foundation he became executive director for Soviet Union and Eastern European Programs at the Institute of International Education. Carmichael holds an AB degree in Economics from Yale University, and a Ph.D. in Economics from Princeton University. He was Dean of the Cornell University Graduate School of Business and Public Administration from 1962-1968.
Organizational History
The administration of Ford Foundation international programs was dramatically restructured in 1980-1981, and a new office for Developing Country Programs was created. William D. Carmichael was appointed Vice President of this new area in March 1981. Carmichael oversaw the work of Foundation field offices, and of New York-based staff responsible for grants to developing countries until 1989.
Scope and Contents
The Office Files of William D. Carmichael document Ford Foundation overseas grants during the period 1968-1989, with an emphasis on the 1980s. The bulk of the records concern Carmichael's work as Vice President, Developing Country Programs, and consist of correspondence, memos and reports pertaining to the administration and grant activities of FF field offices around the world. The collection also documents the relationship between overseas offices of the Ford Foundation and the headquarters in New York City. There are substantial records documenting Carmichael's travel and attendance at conferences, his participation in Board of Trustee meetings and his role in coordinating Board meetings convened overseas. Also included are budget planning records, program review documents, and subject files relating to numerous program initiatives and administrative matters of concern to Carmichael. The collection is particularly rich in material concerning the daily operations of field offices around the world, FF-funded educational programs in South Africa, and the international component of the Foundation's Women's Program.
Arrangement
The Office Files of William D. Carmichael are arranged in six series:
I. Field Offices, 1972-1989 II. South Africa, 1974-1988 III. Conferences, Meetings and Trips, 1981-1988 IV. Program Budget, 1982-1989 V. Subjects, 1968-1989 VI. Board of Trustees, 1978-1989
Conditions Governing Access
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Separated Materials
A list of unpublished reports written by FF staff and consultants were removed from the papers and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. Appendix A lists the reports in alphabetical order by author. The number on the left is the assigned accession number and may be retrieved via the online catalog.
Ford Foundation
- Field Offices, 1972-1989; I
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, press clippings and other records that document program development, grantmaking and grantee activities. Also included are records concerning the establishment, administration and daily operations of overseas offices. Numerous memos and reports written by Program Officers include vivid accounts of the political scene, current events and social and economic conditions in their host countries. Many reports contain general histories of regions or countries, as well as overviews of Foundation activities in these areas. Also included are files (restricted to Ford Foundation staff) concerning the opening of new offices in China and Zimbabwe, and on transferring the West Africa office from Lagos, Nigeria to Dakar, Senegal. The bulk of the series dates from the 1980s, though scattered memos and reports from the 1970s are also present.
  Arrangement
  The records are arranged alphabetically by the region, with further sub-division by program officer.
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Buenos Aires, 1973-1976 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 1)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Consolidation, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 2)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - General, 1973-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 3-4)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Hall, Gridley, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 5)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Lima office consultation – Lowenthal, Abraham, 1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 6)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Puryear, Jeffrey M. (Representative), 1985-1987 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 7-8)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Recife, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 9)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Saint, William S., 1981-1985 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 10)
  - Bangladesh - Bailey, Charles (Representative), 1985-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 11)
  - Bangladesh - Bottrall, Anthony, 1981-1985 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 12)
  - Bangladesh - General, 1982-1988 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 13)
  - Bangladesh - Germain, Adrienne, 1981-1985 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 14)
  - Brazil - Dassin, Joan (Representative), 1987-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 15)
  - Brazil - Fry, Peter, 1986-1988 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 16)
  - Brazil - General, 1981-1988 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 17)
  - Brazil - Reichmann, Rebecca, 1988 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 18)
  - Brazil - Sanderson, Steven, 1987 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 19)
  - Brazil - Sellers, Patricia, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 20)
  - Brazil - Welna, Christopher, 1988 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 21)
  - China - Geithner, Peter F. (Representative), 1982-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 22)
  - China - General, 1979-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 23-24)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Booker, Salih, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 25)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - General, 1981-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 26-29)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Harare, 1983-1989 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 30-32)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Howard, Craig, 1982-1985 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 33)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Hyden, Goran, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (30272), Folder 34)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Hyden, Goran, 1983-1985 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 1-3)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Jones, David, 1982-1985 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 4)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Nairobi office, 1976-1987 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 5)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Saint, William (Representative), 1985-1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 6-7)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Saulniers, Suzanne, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 8)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Chen, Lincoln C. (Representative), 1981-1986 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 9-11)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Conway, Gordon R. (Representative), 1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 12)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Elliott, Carolyn M., 1981-1982 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 13)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - General, 1976-1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 14-15)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Sudarshan, R., 1984-1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 16)
  - Latin American and Caribbean, 1978-1981 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 17)
  - Mexico and Central America - Cleaves, Peter S., 1979-1981 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 18)
  - Mexico and Central America - Cox, Stephen (Representative), 1987-1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 19)
  - Mexico and Central America - General, 1984-1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 20)
  - Mexico and Central America - Welna, Christopher, 1984-1986 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 21)
  - Mexico and Central America - Winder, David, 1982-1985 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 22)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Barsalou, Judy, 1982-1985 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 23)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Cairo Office – Bundy visit, 1975 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 24)
  - Middle East and North Africa - General, 1975-1989 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 25)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Gerhart, John D., 1981-1985 (Box 2 (30273), Folder 26-27)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Lesch, Ann M., 1982-1984 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 1)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Nygaard, David (Representative), 1988-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 2)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Playfair, Emma, 1988-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 3)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Sudan, 1981-1988 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 4)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Travers, Lee (Representative), 1985-1987 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 5)
  - Southeast Asia - General, 1980-1986 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 6-7)
  - Southeast Asia - Kessinger, Tom (Representative), 1982-1986 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 8)
  - Southeast Asia - Korten, Frances, 1982-1988 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 9)
  - Southeast Asia - Office closures, 1973, 1981 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 10)
  - Southeast Asia - Philippines, 1983-1988 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 11)
  - Southeast Asia - Vietnam, 1984 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 12)
  - Southeast Asia - Winder, David (Representative), 1983-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 13)
  - West Africa - Dakar, 1982-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 14-15)
  - West Africa - Duggan, William (Representative), 1986-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 16)
  - West Africa - Ellsworth, Lynn, 1988 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 17)
  - West Africa - General, 1978-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 18-19)
  - West Africa - Horovitz, Richard A. (Representative), 1979-1987 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 20)
  - West Africa - Ivory Coast – Edwards visit, 1975 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 21)
  - West Africa - Joseph, Richard, 1985-1988 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 22)
  - West Africa - Kubisch, Ann, 1987-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 23)
  - West Africa - Lagos, 1981-1989 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 24-25)
  - West Africa - Tragar, Lillian, 1985-1986 (Box 3 (30274), Folder 26)
- South Africa, 1974-1988; II
  Correspondence, memoranda and supporting documents concerning grantmaking and investment in South Africa by the Ford Foundation and other organizations. Includes files of Assistant Program Officer David Bonbright, and records of a committee of foundation and university executives convened by the Carnegie Corporation to promote better educational opportunities for black South Africans.
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Bonbright, David, 1985-1987 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 1)
  - Consortium on Educational Opportunities for Black South Africans, 1985-1986 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 2-4)
  - Firestone, 1985 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 5)
  - Fund for Education in South Africa, 1988 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 6)
  - General, 1974-1988 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 7-14)
- Conferences, Meetings and Trips, 1981-1988; III
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, agendas, reports, program submissions and briefing materials relating to William Carmichael's travel abroad on Foundation business, and his attendance at conferences and meetings worldwide. Events documented in these files include Ford Foundation staff meetings, field office site visits and conferences sponsored by other organizations. Of particular importance are extensive files on the 1985 United Nations Nairobi Conference marking the end of the Women's Decade, the 1983 meetings of the Ford Foundation International Affairs and Human Rights and Social Justice programs in Geneva, Switzerland, and a 1982 New York meeting of Indian Prime Minister Indira Gandhi with representatives of American philanthropies.
  Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Miscellaneous – United States, 1981 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 15)
  - Immigration and Refugee Conference, Williamsburg, VA, 1981 November (Box 4 (30275), Folder 16)
  - Lima, Peru and Bogota, Colombia, 1981 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous – Overseas, 1982 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous – United States, 1982 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 19)
  - Indira Gandhi visit, New York, 1982 August (Box 4 (30275), Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous – Overseas, 1983 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous – United States, 1983 (Box 4 (30275), Folder 22)
  - African-American Institute Conference, Harare, Zimbabwe, 1983 January (Box 4 (30275), Folder 23)
  - International Affairs/Human Rights meeting, Geneva, Switzerland, 1983 January (Box 4 (30275), Folder 24)
  - Indonesia, 1983 March - April (Box 4 (30275), Folder 25)
  - International University Foundation Conference, Ditchley Park, 1983 August (Box 4 (30275), Folder 26)
  - Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1984 January (Box 4 (30275), Folder 27)
  - Central America, 1984 January (Box 4 (30275), Folder 28)
  - Mexico, 1984 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 1-2)
  - Santiago, Chile and Lima, Peru, 1984 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 3)
  - Employment and Income Generation meeting, Bangladesh, 1984 April (Box 5 (30277), Folder 4)
  - International Affairs meeting, Mexico, 1984 April - May (Box 5 (30277), Folder 5)
  - Settling International Disputes Conference, Ditchley Park, 1984 May (Box 5 (30277), Folder 6)
  - Egypt and Israel, 1984 June (Box 5 (30277), Folder 7)
  - Latin American and Caribbean Dinner, Washington, 1984 July (Box 5 (30277), Folder 8)
  - Southern Africa, 1984 July (Box 5 (30277), Folder 9)
  - Prospects for Peace in the Middle East Conference, New York, 1984 September (Box 5 (30277), Folder 10)
  - Dakar, Senegal, 1985 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 11)
  - Haiti, 1985 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 12)
  - SACHED Trust donor meeting, Geneva, Switzerland, 1985 February (Box 5 (30277), Folder 13)
  - Nicaragua, arch, 1985 (Box 5 (30277), Folder 14)
  - Human Rights meeting, Peru, 1985 March (Box 5 (30277), Folder 15)
  - Israel and South Africa, 1985 April (Box 5 (30277), Folder 16)
  - Education and Culture meeting, Bali, 1985 May (Box 5 (30277), Folder 17)
  - Thailand, 1985 May (Box 5 (30277), Folder 18)
  - Meeting with University Presidents about South Africa, Washington, 1985 June (Box 5 (30277), Folder 19)
  - International Affairs meeting, Brazil, 1985 June - July (Box 5 (30277), Folder 20)
  - End of Women's Decade Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, 1985 July (Box 5 (30277), Folder 21-23)
  - World Bank Africa programs meeting, Washington, 1985 September (Box 5 (30277), Folder 24)
  - South Africa, 1985 November (Box 5 (30277), Folder 25)
  - Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1985 December (Box 5 (30277), Folder 26)
  - Mexico, 1986 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 27)
  - South Africa, 1986 February (Box 5 (30277), Folder 28)
  - Child Survival/Population meeting, Katmandu, Nepal, 1986 April (Box 5 (30277), Folder 29)
  - OXFAM meeting, Boston, 1986 June (Box 5 (30277), Folder 30)
  - China, 1986 June - July (Box 5 (30277), Folder 31)
  - South Africa, 1986 July - August (Box 5 (30277), Folder 32)
  - Lagos, Nigeria, 1986 August (Box 5 (30277), Folder 33)
  - Nairobi, Kenya, 1986 August (Box 5 (30277), Folder 34)
  - Europe, 1986 September (Box 5 (30277), Folder 35)
  - Enabling Environment Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, 1986 October (Box 5 (30277), Folder 36)
  - Europe, 1986 November (Box 5 (30277), Folder 37)
  - Rural Poverty and Resources meeting, Nairobi, Kenya, 1986 November (Box 5 (30277), Folder 38)
  - South Africa, 1986 November - December (Box 5 (30277), Folder 39)
  - African-American Institute Conference, Botswana, 1987 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 40-41)
  - Education Policies for Sub-Saharan Africa, Paris, France, 1987 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 42)
  - Human Rights and Governance meeting, London, England, 1987 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 43)
  - Haiti, 1987 February (Box 5 (30277), Folder 44)
  - Angola, 1987 March (Box 5 (30277), Folder 45)
  - Peru, 1987 May (Box 5 (30277), Folder 46)
  - Angolan Economy/African-American Institute Conferences, Tarrytown, 1987 June (Box 5 (30277), Folder 47)
  - Nicaragua, 1987 June (Box 5 (30277), Folder 48)
  - South Africa, 1987 September (Box 5 (30277), Folder 49)
  - African-American Institute Conference, Maryland, 1987 November (Box 5 (30277), Folder 50)
  - West Africa, 1987 November (Box 5 (30277), Folder 51)
  - World Health Organization AIDS Conference, Switzerland, 1987 November (Box 5 (30277), Folder 52)
  - Future of the Front-line States in Southern Africa, Ditchley Park, 1988 January (Box 5 (30277), Folder 53)
  - Latin America staff meeting, 1988 February (Box 5 (30277), Folder 54)
  - Non-Profit and International Organizations Forum, New York, 1988 February (Box 6 (30278), Folder 1)
  - Haiti, 1988 March (Box 6 (30278), Folder 2)
  - Indonesia, 1988 March (Box 6 (30278), Folder 3)
  - Asia/Rural Poverty and Governance meeting, India, 1988 April (Box 6 (30278), Folder 4)
  - Colloquium on Development, Massachusetts, 1988 May (Box 6 (30278), Folder 5)
  - Income Generation meetings, Nairobi, Kenya, 1988 May (Box 6 (30278), Folder 6)
  - South Africa, 1988 May (Box 6 (30278), Folder 7)
  - American Grantmaking in South Africa, Washington, 1988 June (Box 6 (30278), Folder 8)
  - Haiti, 1988 June (Box 6 (30278), Folder 9)
  - Philippines, 1988 August (Box 6 (30278), Folder 10)
  - Education Initiatives for Black South Africans, Oxford, England, 1988 September (Box 6 (30278), Folder 11)
  - North-South Roundtable Meeting on South Africa, Zimbabwe, 1988 December (Box 6 (30278), Folder 12)
- Program Budget, 1982-1989; IV
  Program budget submissions and related documentation from DCP and a few other Foundation divisions. Many files include substantive reports on the political, social, and economic climates of various countries in which the Foundation had offices. The Program Review files contained in Series V are closely related to these budget materials.
  - Andes and Southern Cone, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 13-14)
  - Bangladesh, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 15-16)
  - Brazil, 1982-1987 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 17)
  - Child Survival/Fair Start, 1984 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 18)
  - Caribbean and Latin America, 1982-1987 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 19)
  - China, 1984-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 20)
  - Developing Country Programs, 1984-1988 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 21-22)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 23-24)
  - Education and Culture, 1984-1985 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 25)
  - Foundation-wide, 1986-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 26)
  - Governance and Public Policy, 1984-1985 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 27)
  - Human Rights and Social Justice, 1984-1985 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 28)
  - India, Nepal, Sri Lanka, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 29-30)
  - International Affairs, 1984-1985 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 31)
  - Israel, 1982-1987 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 32)
  - Mexico and Central America, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 33)
  - Middle East and North Africa, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 34)
  - Rural Poverty and Resources, 1984-1985 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 35)
  - South Africa, 1982-1987 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 36)
  - Southeast Asia, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 37)
  - Urban Poverty, 1984-1985 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 38)
  - West Africa, 1982-1989 (Box 6 (30278), Folder 39)
- Subjects, 1968-1989; V
  Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Series contains records concerning miscellaneous program initiatives, administrative matters, outside organizations and topics of general interest to Carmichael. Included are DCP program review files, memos and reports concerning the origins of the Women's Program and the Health, Nutrition and Population Program, and correspondence concerning the Bilateral Commission on United States-Mexican Relations (access to the latter is restricted to Ford Foundation staff).
  Conditions Governing Access
  Select files are restricted from scholarly access as noted.
  - Affirmative Action – Ford Foundation Policy, 1974-1978 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 1)
  - AIDS Task Force, 1987-1988 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 2)
  - Atlanta University, 1979-1980 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 3)
  - Bilateral Commission on the Future of U.S.-Mexican Relations, 1984-1989 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 4-9)
    Restricted from scholarly access.
  - Boston University Health Policy Institute, 1980 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 10)
  - Chronological correspondence file, 1975-1976 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 11-13)
  - Council on Foreign Relations – Current Issue Review Group on Cuba, 1975 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 14)
  - Council on Foreign Relations – Discussion Group on African Development, 1972-1976 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 15)
  - Council on Foreign Relations – Discussion Group on the Soviet Union in Africa, 1978-1979 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 16)
  - Education – Myers, Robert G., 1981-1984 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 17)
  - Ethnic Conflict in Developing Countries, 1977-1982 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 18-19)
  - External Advisory Panel on Education, 1978-1979 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 20)
  - Financial accounting software, 1986-1989 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 21)
  - Fulbright Exchange Program Conference, 1980 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 22)
  - Health, Nutrition and Population, 1976-1978 (Box 7 (30279), Folder 23)
  - Health, Nutrition and Population, 1979-1981 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 1-4)
  - Human Rights, 1978-1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 5)
  - Institute of Cultural Affairs, 1982-1984 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 6)
  - International Division Conference, 1978-1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 7)
  - International Division Conference – Special Papers, 1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 8)
  - International Division Education Conference, 1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 9)
  - International Economic Order, 1975-1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 10)
  - International Human Rights Internship Program, 1988 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 11)
  - International Security and Arms Control, 1979-1980 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 12)
  - Interns, 1973-1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 13)
  - Korten, David C., 1980-1982 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 14)
  - Liberian refugees, 1980 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 15)
  - Mid-decade Review, 1986-1987 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 16-18)
  - National Development Models, 1978-1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 19)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1974-1977 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 20)